<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Async]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Web Tech Meetup for Brighton & Hove]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 20:17:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asyncjs.com/feed/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[An Introduction to Gatsby and Gatsby Themes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What is <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/">Gatsby</a>? Learn how you can use it to build performant web apps and sites. We’ll cover getting started, sourcing data, and some of Gatsby’s built-in performance optimisations. To finish up we’ll learn about the future of Gatsby with Gatsby Themes.</p>
<p>A basic understanding of <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React.js</a> is assumed.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/gatsby</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/gatsby</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/875556871427375106/Xuq8DypK_400x400.jpg</url><title>Gatsby logo</title><link>https://www.gatsbyjs.org/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Mike Allanson ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Semprola, a semiotic programming language]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Most programming languages are built on ideas that were developed in the 1950s and 1960s and yet a lot about how we use computers has changed since then. Brighton local Oli Sharpe has been researching ideas about how one would build a contemporary programming language given how we use computers today. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.shift-society.org/salon/papers/2018/revised/semprola.pdf">Semprola</a> is the programming language he is developing as a result of this research. The Async talk will first give a brief overview of the thinking behind the ideas of Semprola, a language in which you work with semiotic signs in contexts rather than symbols in text files. Then there will be a brief demo of where Semprola is at today, followed by a short explanation of the way that Javascript is being used to create the (rudimentary!) integrated Semprola IDE.</p>
<p>This won&#39;t be a deep dive into the compiler (or VM!) but the audience will be assumed to have basic understanding of programming.</p>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by Creative Technologies, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/semprola</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/semprola</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/3931/15415543906_0a9254d3e2_z_d.jpg</url><title>Semiotic architecture</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/enfamous2j/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Oli Sharpe ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Brains Spring 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>After last year&#39;s successful <a href="https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-18/">Ask the Brains</a> event, we&#39;ll be rebooting it for 2019.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">Brighton ALT.NET meetup</a> also hosted at the Skiff, we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web related - 10 minutes per topic. The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Should I use Flow JS or TypeScript for my new app? Why?</li>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does &#39;this&#39; mean in Javascript?</li>
<li>How big do I let a project get before using Redux?</li>
<li>What actually is a database index anyway?</li>
<li>What VS Code plugins can you not live without?</li>
<li>Is it just me, or is React Router 5 rubbish?</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
</ul>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner, or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask, so you can come prepared!</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://madgex.com/uk/careers#vacancies">Madgex</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-19</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-19</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/4138/4932655275_9af8d4e8b6_n_d.jpg</url><title>What?</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/debord/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[React Hooks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The highly anticipated feature of React Hooks has finally been released. We can now add state and use side effects in our functional React components.</p>
<p>We are going to take a look at the precursors to Hooks, then learn about how Hooks work and how to use them to improve our React apps.</p>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by Creative Technologies, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/react-hooks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/react-hooks</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/58/Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg/512px-Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg</url><title>Fishing hooks on white surface</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fishing_hooks_on_white_surface.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Matthew McCorry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Imposter Syndrome]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Imposter syndrome. You may have heard of it. You may have suffered from it. You might not even have realised it at the time.</p>
<p>This talk will explore a journey through imposter syndrome: recognition, acceptance and coping strategies.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: It won&#39;t contain a magic cure, but hopefully some of it will help!</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>Brandwatch will now be sponsoring! Free beers &amp; pizzas for all. Please contact hello AT asyncjs DOT com if you have specific dietary requirements.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/imposter-syndrome</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/imposter-syndrome</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https:////c1.staticflickr.com/3/2807/9128471890_77a27cc811_h.jpg</url><title>Imposter!</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/42714088@N07/9128471890/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Pete ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[govuk-react - our UI component library and CI pipeline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>govuk-react is a React component library for building govuk-styled web applications. We will be giving a demo of its usage, an overview of the technologies used to develop it and show our continuous integration setup including visual regression tests and preview environments.</p>
<p>This will be useful for anyone interested in:</p>
<ul>
<li>automated tests and CI pipelines for UI focussed code</li>
<li>building UI component libraries or design systems</li>
<li>React</li>
</ul>
<p>Alasdair McLeay and Steve Sims are freelance UI developers, currently working on a large public sector project for IBM.</p>
<h3 id="update">Update</h3>
<p>Brandwatch have stepped in at the last moment to offer sponsorship, hooray! Free beers &amp; pizzas for all. Please contact hello AT asyncjs DOT com if you have specific dietary requirements.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/govuk-react</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/govuk-react</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a7/React-icon.svg/512px-React-icon.svg.png</url><title>React icon</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:React-icon.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Alasdair McLeay, Steve Sims ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebGL with Dan Neame]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Dan Neame will be kicking off the new Async year with a talk on WebGL. Please note that it&#39;ll be on the <em>second</em> Thursday of the month, to allow us all time recover from our festive hangover! </p>
<p>Dan will be talking about the following topics in ThreeJS:</p>
<ul>
<li>Basics</li>
<li>Geometry</li>
<li>Materials</li>
<li>Postprocessing</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://madgex.com/uk/careers#vacancies">Madgex</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/webgl</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/webgl</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/25/WebGL_Logo.svg</url><title>Khronos Group [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:WebGL_Logo.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dan Neame ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Useable, Grammatical and Readable code]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As software developers, we all know that we need to make our code more readable - but how exactly? There is not a lot of literature out there on the subject, and what there is can be very dogmatic and contradictory.</p>
<p>In this talk, Daniel van Berzon attempts to tackle the issue by learning from the worlds of Linguistics and UX, which have successfully solved similar problems. As part of the talk Daniel will present the initial findings from his ongoing readability experiment at <a href="http://howreadable.com">howreadable.com</a>.</p>
<p>Anyone who has written some code, used a website and tried to speak a language (including English) should enjoy this talk.</p>
<h1 id="update-">Update:</h1>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://ocasta.com">Ocasta</a>, so drinks and pizzas for all! This session, all pizzas will be from <a href="http://purezza.co.uk/">Purezza</a>, so no need to let us know dietary requirements except for gluten free as they&#39;ll all be vegan/vegetarian :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/readable-code</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/readable-code</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3684/13607959244_bab2160c1a_z_d.jpg</url><title>The Wolf Law Library</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/wolflawlibrary/13607959244</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2018 International Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The November migration of the world&#39;s top web developers to the sunny city of Brighton &amp; Hove can only mean one thing - <a href="http://2018.ffconf.org/">FFConf 2018</a> is coming. So, it&#39;s time for another <strong>International Async Show&#39;n&#39;tell</strong>! This year&#39;s instalment will be <em>on Wednesday 7th November</em> - not Thursday. The ever popular International show&#39;n&#39;tell is the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind.</p>
<p><em>If you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web. We hope to bring together a blend of local projects with those from travellers to England for the conference.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/larister/ab84a296acf8f6cc51e242ea40dd53ac">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
<h2 id="important-notice-">Important Notice:</h2>
<p>For the Show&#39;n&#39;Tell we&#39;ll be back in our old venue of <a href="http://68middle.st">68 Middle St</a>, <em>not</em> The Skiff</p>
<h1 id="update-">Update:</h1>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by <a href="https://ocasta.com">Ocasta</a>, so drinks and pizzas for all! This session, all pizzas will be from <a href="http://purezza.co.uk/">Purezza</a>, so no need to let us know dietary requirements except for gluten free as they&#39;ll all be vegan/vegetarian :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3289/3060694963_3d778f69dd_z_d.jpg</url><title>The Juggler II</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/helico</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ All and sundry ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Supercharged Spreadsheets]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We all know the struggle, when a feature request sounds like the perfect job for a spreadsheet. But... there&#39;s always a tiny detail that makes us believe it&#39;s not quite enough to do the job. Or is it? In this talk, Tibor Besze will demonstrate how to utilise Google Apps Scripts (and a wide variety of Google services and APIs) to get the most out of your Google Sheets. The talk is aimed at Javascript developers of all skill levels, and includes a live demonstration.</p>
<h2 id="update-">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by <a href="http://www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/supercharged-spreadsheets</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/supercharged-spreadsheets</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://miro.medium.com/max/1054/1*u-AcMWWeLrVVs7gj0QyBOQ.png</url><title>Google Sheets logo</title><link>https://chatbotsmagazine.com/build-a-bot-with-zero-coding-on-google-sheets-922f20d80c51</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tibor Besze ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Double bill - Electron and Unit Testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>October will see the return of the famed Async &quot;Double Bills&quot;.</p>
<p>Part 1: Testing JavaScript by Mark Everitt</p>
<p>A whistle-stop tour of why, what, when, and how to test. This talk should be relevant to all JS coders, from those just starting out to seasoned developers.</p>
<p>Part 2: Electron.js by Dan Neame</p>
<p>Electron allows you to package your web apps as executable Desktop applications. In this talk Dan Neame will cover how Electron works, how to get started with the framework, how to build a complicated application, and how to package these for release across Windows, Linux and Mac.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/career/full-stack-engineer">Rakuten Marketing</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/double-bill-electron-n-unit-testing</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/double-bill-electron-n-unit-testing</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1873/29163684827_51640f9e0d_z_d.jpg</url><title>Double rainbow</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/snowpeak/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Dan Neame, Mark Everitt ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Compression]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve always been amazed about how compression formats and algorithms work. Over the past couple of years, I have created a game that features a hand-rolled compression algorithm for the game maps. These consist of two 2D arrays of numbers, corresponding to the game tiles. However, this format can be applied to an integer array of any number of dimensions.</p>
<p>This talk will be about how the compression algorithm works, including condensing the information and then translating to binary, before finally writing to disk.</p>
<h2 id="update-">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will again be sponsored by the good folk at <a href="http://www.prodpad.com/about-us/jobs/">ProdPad</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/compression</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/compression</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4785420782_4196588df4_z_d.jpg</url><title>M113 - Car Crusher 2</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/tncountryfan/4785420782</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Niall Coleman ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[React Native]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Over the recent years, various attempts have been made to bring app development to the web development community, with varying degrees of success and popularity. Facebook&#39;s offering asks devs to leverage their knowledge of React and its ecosystem, but ditch the DOM, to allow for frictionless development of performant iOS and Android apps. However, with their &quot;learn once, write anywhere&quot; approach, is React Native really as straightforward as the marketing blurb would have you believe? In this talk, we&#39;ll cover how easy it is to get your React Native code running on a real device, offer a primer to the React and JSX way of life, and discuss some of the hurdles you might come across.</p>
<h2 id="update-">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by the good folk at <a href="http://www.prodpad.com/about-us/jobs/">ProdPad</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/react-native</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/react-native</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a7/React-icon.svg/500px-React-icon.svg.png</url><title>React Native Logo</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:React-icon.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ David Sharp ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alexa workshop]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon tutorials will help you make your first Hello World/Alexa app, but what then? Building a Voice User Interface raises questions that will apply to any app build. Jez will take you on a lightning tour of what he has learned so far. There will be slides+talk, there will be activities, there will be live(ish) coding. You should leave the session with an idea of how Alexa works and what a real-life project might involve..</p>
<p>This meetup will be sponsored by Creative Technologies, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/alexa-apps</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/alexa-apps</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/cc/Amazon_Alexa_App_Logo.png</url><title>Amazon Alexa App Logo</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Amazon_Alexa_App_Logo.png</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Jez Nicholson ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intro to Rust]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Rust is a new language developed by Mozilla which takes an interesting approach to memory management and memory safety. We&#39;ll be taking a look at Rust&#39;s &quot;big idea&quot; and the thing that makes it unique; ownership and borrowing. This language level feature forms the cornerstone of Rust and is a common source of trouble for people picking up the language.</p>
<p>We&#39;ll take a brief look at how to get started with Rust before diving into some very simple code examples that introduce the core language, drawing special attention to the mechanics of ownership and borrowing.</p>
<h2 id="update-">UPDATE:</h2>
<p>This meetup will now be sponsored by <a href="http://www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a>, so beers and pizzas for all! If you have any dietary requirements, please get in touch at <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-rust</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/intro-to-rust</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e1/Rusty_steam_locomotive_in_Tua_train_station.jpg/640px-Rusty_steam_locomotive_in_Tua_train_station.jpg</url><title>Rusty steam locomotive in Tua train station</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Rusty_steam_locomotive_in_Tua_train_station.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Oliver Winks ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;m fascinated by how websites are built and released in to the world. I&#39;ve been doing it in all sorts of ways for over fifteen years at companies like Microsoft, the Guardian, Twitter, and currently Brandwatch in Brighton. Over that time I&#39;ve got somewhat opinionated about effective ways of releasing things on the web, whether that&#39;s web frontends, APIs, or cloud infrastructure.</p>
<p>I think there are some core methodologies to developing, testing, building, and deploying software that lead to rapid, high quality, low-risk releases. Methodologies that empower developers and designers to get their work in front of users quickly, leading to better products and a much more rewarding and reliable way of developing.</p>
<p>We&#39;ll talk through some of these methodologies and principles, and look at some specific implementations and examples.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/continuous-delivery</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/continuous-delivery</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5126/5369581593_b9e2ec903c_z_d.jpg</url><title>Container Ship</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/usoceangov/5369581593</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Andy Hume ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Show n' Tell Spring 2018]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It&#39;s 2018 and after a few great talks, and our new <a href="https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains/">Ask The Brains</a> evening of tech discussion, we&#39;re back with another Show n&#39; Tell! Last year we had a great range of projects and topics ranging from creative CSS animations and generating &quot;marble flow&quot; textures in real time, to taking a look at some emerging languages and proposals for unit testing tools. And, not to forget, we had our youngest ever speaker, at only 8 years old, showing off a javascript game they had made.</p>
<p>Come along and see what awesome stuff the community has been working on, share your own projects, or talk about something you&#39;re passionate about. We&#39;d love to see you there.</p>
<p><em>If you’d like to grab a speaking slot</em>, you’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, HTML, CSS, or the wider world of tech.</p>
<p>Speakers, please <a data-gist href="https://gist.github.com/JakeSidSmith/45e60f8c45ab5128d760d33de7c3e3e1">add a comment to the Speakers&#39; Gist</a>.</p>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, check out our previous show n&#39; tells: <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">International 2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">International 2016</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2016/">Spring 2016</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">International 2015</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/showntell-spring-2015/">Spring 2015</a>, or view all of our <a href="https://asyncjs.com/events/">previous events</a>.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p><a href="https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/career/full-stack-engineer">Rakuten Marketing</a> are kindly sponsoring again, so they&#39;ll provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/show-n-tell-spring-2018</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/show-n-tell-spring-2018</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/fractals/1.jpg</url><title>Fractal</title><link>/img/fractals/1.jpg</link></image></item><item><title><![CDATA[Limitation breeds creativity]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In web dev, sometimes the sheer volume of things to learn can be overwhelming. Pair this with anxiety and a tendency to procrastinate and you’ve got the perfect recipe for doing absolutely nothing.</p>
<p>More choice doesn’t mean more creativity. When you work within constraints your mind has to look for unconventional ways around it. Come along to see me demo a few of my favourite unconventional solutions. (Some restrictions were even self inflicted.) </p>
<p>Expect LOTS of CSS, and a bunch of (hopefully) clever hacks.</p>
<h2 id="update">Update</h2>
<p>This meeting will be sponsored by <a href="https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/career/full-stack-engineer">Rakuten Marketing</a>, who will provide pizzas and beers for all. Please get in touch if you have any specific dietary requirements at hello AT asyncjs DOT com.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/limitation-breeds-creativity</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/limitation-breeds-creativity</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3759/9375675955_d1bc16555f_z_d.jpg</url><title>Bristol born escape artist Roslyn Walker</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/brizzlebornandbred/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Cassie Evans ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Brains]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>And now for something a little different. This session, the content will be in your hands. Rather than having one speaker speaking on one topic, we&#39;ll be covering a range of topics chosen on the night, and leveraging the power of the mighty brains of Async to demystify, enlighten, and wax lyrical.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">Brighton ALT.NET meetup</a> also hosted at the Skiff, we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web related - 10 minutes per topic. The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Should I use Flow JS or TypeScript for my new app? Why?</li>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does &#39;this&#39; mean in Javascript?</li>
<li>How big do I let a project get before using Redux?</li>
<li>What actually is a database index anyway?</li>
<li>What VS Code plugins can you not live without?</li>
<li>Is it just me, or is React Router 4 rubbish?</li>
<li>Which Javascript unit testing framework should I use?</li>
</ul>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner, or a seasoned pro, please do come and join!</p>
<h3 id="update-">Update:</h3>
<p>The link for the Global Diversity CFP workshop is <a href="https://www.globaldiversitycfpday.com/events/60">here</a>; do come along and spread the word!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-18</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-18</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2257/3534516458_48e4e8595f_z_d.jpg</url><title>Question mark</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/marcobellucci/3534516458</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firebase]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ve all had that night where we get a great idea for a side project, and to make it really great it needs to have authentication, persistent state, some sort of backend to handle the stuff we can&#39;t expose to the frontend. If you think it&#39;s a really great idea you might even throw in some analytics.</p>
<p>You start off by looking at what&#39;s the ~cheapest~ best server you can spin up... is it a Droplet or a Dyno this month? Ubuntu or CentOS? Probably need some Docker or Chef to make sure you always redeploy it correctly. Now you can make a start on that Rest API... ah yeah Express, KOA? MongoDB connector, is Mongoose still a thing? Don&#39;t forget to set up those JWTs correctly.</p>
<p>At this point you&#39;re still having fun... who doesn&#39;t like building a clean, secure and well documented REST API and hitting it up with Postman (those automated testing features are amazing).</p>
<p>Seriously it&#39;s really rewarding to get all that set up and working, but by the time I get to the building the idea I&#39;m all funned out and it just becomes another directory in my projects folder.</p>
<p>Google&#39;s Firebase suite of tools get you up and running with <em>everything</em> in minutes, so you can focus on that awesome life changing idea.</p>
<p>Come down for a run down on the tools to get your web app up and running.</p>
<p><strong>Bring a laptop</strong> if you can, we&#39;ll be forming into teams to put your Firebase skills to the test in a chain reaction game to be the first team to send your rocket to Mars.</p>
<h3 id="about-the-speaker">About the speaker</h3>
<p>Harry is a Javascript developer at <a href="http://www.brandwatch.com">Brandwatch</a> who just loves all parts of development... but mostly frontend.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/firebase</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/firebase</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://firebase.google.com/_static/images/firebase/touchicon-180.png</url><title>Firebase logo</title><link>https://firebase.google.com/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Harry Hogg ]]</author></item></channel></rss>